Photograph album
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Photograph album
2.1.6
Marist College
  Box 1597
- Photograph album, 2.1.6
  - High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (New Guinea), 1957; 1 (Box 1597)
    - Page 1: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives canoing. 2 - Native standing on canoe with paddle in hand, 1
    - Page 2: Two photos on page. 1 - Mountain in distance. 2 - Native woman with a tool raised above her head., 2
    - Page 3: Two photos on page. 1 - Woman hacking out canoes with hand-made tools. 2 - Natives paddling in canoes, 3
    - Page 4: Two photos on page. 1 - Woman with hand-made tool raised above her head, making a canoe. 2 - Natives in canoes, 4
    - Page 5: Two photos on page. 1 - Boat on water, passing by native huts. 2 - Natives with canoes, huts in the background, 5
    - Page 6: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives in canoes and on dock. 2 - Women working on canoes with hand-made tools, 6
    - Page 7: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives paddling in canoes. 2 - Natives paddling in canoes, 7
    - Page 8: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives standing in canoes. 2 - Boat on water, 8
    - Page 9: Six photos on page. 1 - Lines of canoes, lying face down. Large boat in background. 2 - Canoes lying face down, large boat in background. 3 - The back of a man on a boat. 4 - Boat floating on water in front of hut. 5 - Woman examining a man's arm. 6 - People loading objects onto a plane (?), 9
    - Page 10: Six photos on page. 1 - Natives working on canoes. 2 - Natives working on canoes in front of a hut. 3 - Native woman paddling a canoe. 4 - Native woman. 5 - Boat anchored by land. 6 - Boat anchored by land., 10
    - Page 11: Six photos on page. 1 - Man sitting with feet in the water, holding a camera to take a picture of a native woman working on a canoe with handmade tools. Two other men watching from behind. 2 - Man with camera, filming. 3 - Natives observing airplane. 4 - Close-up of man walking. 5 - People and supplies beside the airplane. 6 - Native carrying box over shoulder, airplane in background, 11
    - Page 12: Six photos on page. 1 - Natives working on canoes. 2 - Man on dock, under an umbrella with a camera, filming. 3 - Man drinking from a coconut. 4 - Canoes out on water with huts in the background. 5 - Close-up of a native woman. 6 - Close-up of a native woman, 12
    - Page 13: Two photos on page. 1 - Men watching the woman work on canoes. Film equipment set off to the left. 2 - Large group of people with huts in background., 13
    - Page 14: Two photos on page. 1 - Line of soldiers and three men standing in front of them. 2 - Boat riding by on the water., 14
    - Page 15: Two photos on page. 1 - Group of native warriors. 2 - Boat on water., 15
    - Page 16: Six photos on page. 1 - Group of natives facing away. 2 - Group of natives on dock with unidentified man. 3 - Camera crew on dock, filming. 4 - Camera crew on dock, breaking down? 5 - Woman carving canoe, others in background. 6 - Man poleing flatboat with camera crew onboard., 16
    - Page 17: Two photos on page. 1 - Group of natives, dancing. 2 - Camera crew preparing to film woman making canoe., 17
    - Page 18: Two photos on page. 1 -Groups of natives on canoes and a boat pointing in their direction. 2 - Native woman paddling a canoe., 18
    - Page 19: Two photos on page. 1 -Three soldiers with rifles. 2 - Group of people with supplies on dock, man filming them., 19
    - Page 20: Two photos on page. 1 - Native warriors and a man filming them. 2 - Men filming the native warriors., 20
    - Page 21: Two photos on page. 1 - Nighttime; man sitting on boat playing the accordian with the natives listening. 2 - Nighttime; man sitting on boat playing the accordian with the natives listening, 21
    - Page 22: Two photos on page. 1 - Nighttime; Natives on canoe near boat with men on it. 2 - Nighttime; from point of view of the dock with a latern lit on it; Natives on canoe near boat with men on it., 22
    - Page 23: Two photos on page. 1 - Man talking to natives with New Guinea soldiers standing behind him. 2 - Men on boat with lighting equpiment, 23
    - Page 24: Two photos on page. 1 -Two men sitting, with natives standing behind them. 2 - Men gathererd on dock by boat., 24
    - Page 25: Six photos on page. 1 - Man and woman on boat. 2 - Two women looking at papers on boat, man in between them pointing to a sheet. 3 - Man looking out on boat. 4 - Man looking out on dock (?). 5 - Native children standing in a line. 6 - Man observing machinery., 25
    - Page 26: Six photos on page. 1 - Men filming boat from other boat. 2 - Two men reading papers on a boat. 3 - Man with one foot on dock and the other on boat. 4 - Natives standing around a canoe. 5 - Two men working on a boat. 6 - Native sittingon a boat making a basket (?)., 26
    - Page 27: Two photos on page. 1 - Native women working on canoes with hand-made tools. 2 - Boat on water, 27
    - Page 28: Two photos on page. 1 - One large boat and one small boat on water. 2 - One large boat and one small boat on water, 28
    - Page 29: Two photos on page. 1 - Smaller boat on water. 2 - Man lighting a cigarette on boat, two other boats to the right, 29
    - Page 30: Two photos on page. 1 - Nighttime; Men on dock (?) with latern watching a boat on the water. Natives on oppposite dock. 2 - People in hut. Man sleeping in a net covered cot on left, 30
    - Page 31: Two photos on page. 1 - Nighttime; Natives on dock watching boat on water. 2 - Nighttime; men with camera equipment looking out across at natives on dock and boat on the water., 31
    - Page 32: Two photos on page. 1 - Nighttime; Man sitting on net covered cot, putting on shoes. 2 - Nighttime; Natives standing on canoe, 32
    - Page 33: Two photos on page. 1 - Nighttime; People with camera equipment, man standing in a lighted hut. 2 - Nighttime; people with camera equipment, others in lighted hut, 33
    - Page 34: Two photos on page. 1 - Nighttime; Latern on dock, Natives on opposite dock watching boat on water. 2 - Two boats, one with men and camera equipment, 34
    - Page 35: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives on dock, watching boat on water. 2 - Two boats on the water in the distance., 35
    - Page 36: Two photos on page. 1 - People walking on dock that leads up to a hill with a hut on it. Boat tied to dock. 2 - Boat tied to dock. Close-up of people walking up to the hill, 36
    - Page 37: Two photos on page. 1 - Men disembarking from boat. 2 - Two boats following each other on the water. Men filming the boat ahead from second boat, 37
    - Page 38: Two photos on page. 1 - Painted natives carrying branches. 2 - Two men holding a type of instrument, 38
    - Page 39: Two photos on page. 1 - Native men working on a handcraft. 2 - Lines of natives moving in an orderly form, 39
    - Page 40: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Natives holding spears in front of large hut. 2 - Natives dancing in decorative costumes. 3 - Natives holding spears. 4 - Natives paddling canoes by edge of land with huts., 40
    - Page 41: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Two boats on water. 2 - Two natives ordorned with jewelry, one smoking a bong. 3 - Washed out photo. Native odorned with jewelry. 4 - Native woman, standing, 41
    - Page 42: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Native with elaborate headdress. Another native lying on stomach. 2 - Woman using hand-made tool to work on canoe. 3 - Line of huts. 4 - Boat on water, 42
    - Page 43: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - People around canoes on land. 2 - Natives holding spears, standing around large hut. 3 - Two men helping native woman out of canoe. 4 - People on dock around tied down boat, 43
    - Page 44: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Native men sitting down wearing elebarate jewelry. 2 - Nighttime, two boats on water with laterns. 3 - Native with feathered headdress using some type of instrument. 4 - Man with painted face holding a spear., 44
    - Page 45: Six photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Native men with spears standing around a large hut. 2 - Native women standing. 3 - Natives, some standing some sitting. 4 - Native men around hut. 5 - Men walking. 6 - Natives standing around canoe in water, 45
    - Page 46: Two photos on page. 1 - Native woman standing. 2 - Men disembarking from boat., 46
    - Page 47: Two photos on page. 1 - Boat on water. 2 - People on boat by dock, 47
    - Page 48: Six photos on page. 1 - Man with cigarrette standing on boat. 2 - Man stepping from dock onto boat. 3 - People on boat in water. 4 - Man crouched by large light. 5 - Boat on water. 6 - Men with camera equipment, 48
    - Page 49: Six photos on page. 1 - Boat on water. 2 - Boat on water. 3 - Man sitting around supplies on boat. 4 - Men working on camera equipment. 5 - Man looking through camera, filming. 6 - Man looking through camera, filming, 49
    - Page 50: Six photos on page. 1 - Boat on water. 2 - Boat at dock. 3 - People around boxes on dock. 4 - People around boxes on dock. 5 - Man filiming on dock. 6 - Woman examining a man's arm, 50
    - Page 51: Six photos on page. 1 - Native woman paddling canoe with child on shoulders. 2 - Native man holding spear by hut. 3 - People on dock loading onto boat. 4 - Natives in hut. 5 - Natives in canoes on water. 6 - Native woman., 51
    - Page 52: Two photos on page. 1 - Four young native women standing. 2 - People around boxes on dock. Man filming., 52
    - Page 53: Two photos on page. 1 - Native women sitting on steps to hut. 2 - People standing around huts., 53
    - Page 54: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives in canoes on water. 2 - Natives paddling canoes, others on boat., 54
    - Page 55: Two photos on page. 1 - Small crowd of natives standing around hut. Men with camera equipment. 2 - Painted native man., 55
    - Page 56: Two photos on page. 1 - Small crowd of natives standing around hut. Man filming. 2 - Native man on boat working on a basket (?), 56
    - Page 57: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives with shields and spears. Men filming. 2 - Native men with shields and spears standing around a hut., 57
    - Page 58: Two photos on page. 1 - Inside hut. Natives dancing with unusal costumes that cover their entire bodies spare their feet. Man filming. 2 - Crowd of natives around large hut., 58
    - Page 59: Two photos on page. 1 - Native women standing in rows. 2 - Native men wearing jewelry, one holding spear., 59
    - Page 60: Six photos on page. 1 - Men on boat with filming equipment. 2 - Boat on water. 3 - Boat on water. 4 - Men sitting on boat with filming equipment. 5 - Two boats on water in distance. 6 - People on boat., 60
    - Page 61: Six photos on page. 1 - Men on boat with camera. 2 - Natives standing, one sitting on a hand-made stool. 3 - Men sitting on boat. 4 - Boat on water. 5 - Natives standing by a canoe that is in the process of being furnished. 6 - Two boats on water., 61
    - Page 62: Six photos on page. 1 - Close-up of man with painted face and necklace made of shells. 2 - People on dock with supplies. 3 - Native man with headdress. 4 - People on boat. Canoe pulled up to side of boat. 5 - Group of natives standing around canoe that is in the process of being furnished. 6 - Small group of native women, 62
    - Page 63: Six photos on page. 1 - From point of view on boat on water, looking hut on land. 2 - Line of native women standing. 3 - Native woman standing. 4 - Boat on water. 5 - Men on boat with camera equipment. 6 - Boat on water., 63
    - Page 64: Six photos on page. 1 - Native child standing. 2 - Painted natives standing in a group. 3 - Small crowd of natives. 4 - Native man sitting wearing hand-made jewelry. 5 - Close-up of native man wearing hand-made jewelry. 6 - Close-up of native man wearing hand-made jewelry, 64
    - Page 65: Six photos on page. 1 - Native men wearing hand-made jewelry. 2 - Native men wearing hand-made jewelry. 3 - Men on boat. One man demonstrating something. Camera equipment on boat. 4 - Line of canoes in the process of being furnished. 5 - Native man and woman standing on canoe. 6 - Woman standing on canoe., 65
    - Page 66: Six photos on page. 1 - Man and woman sitting looking over papers. 2 - People on boat. 3 - Native man on boat with one foot rested against canoe. 4 - Native men in exotic costumes, dancing. 5 - Native men in exotic costumes, dancing. 6 - Native wearing elaborate costume, 66
    - Page 67: Six photos on page. 1 - Native man and child sitting, man smoking a bong. 2 - Two native men and child sitting, one man smoking a bong. 3 - Two native men sitting, one smoking a bong. 4 - Native man smoking a bong. 5 - Native man sitting, smoking a bong. 6 - Two native men sitting and eating., 67
    - Page 68: Two photos on page. 1 - Boat on water. 2 - Three native women, standing., 68
    - Page 69: Two photos on page. 1 - Camera crew on flatboat filming natives in canoe. 2 - Boat in water., 69
    - Page 70: Two photos on page. 1 - Lowell Thomas posing with group of natives. 2 - Lowell Thomas posing with two natives with bows., 70
    - Page 71: Four photos on page. 1 - People on boat; native working on a basket (?), Lowell Thomas sitting in background. 2 - People sitting on boat with filming equipment. 3 - Man and woman sitting underneath roof of boat; New Guinea officer standing outside. 4 - Two men sitting on boat, talking., 71
    - Page 72: Two photos on page. 1 - Lowell Thomas with microphone talking, script in hand, and two native women on each side of him. 2 - Lowell Thomas standing with two native men., 72
    - Page 73: Two photos on page. 1 - Lowell Thomas with two native men who are showing him a canoe. 2 - Lowell Thomas sitting between two native men who are holding bows and arrows., 73
    - Page 74: Two photos on page. 1 - Officer on boat; Lowell Thomas sitting. 2 - Lowell Thomas walking with men following., 74
    - Page 75: Two photos on page. 1 - Lowell Thomas sitting with the natives 2 - Lowell Thomas sitting with natives who are holding bows and arrows., 75
    - Page 76: Four photos on page. 1 - Lowell Thomas on boat looking over papers with the other men. 2 - Men atanding around boxes and talking to a native man. 3 - Men standing on a boat with supplies; Lowell Thomas in background. 4 - Men standing on boat; Lowell Thomas in background., 76
    - Page 77: Two photos on page. (Color photos) 1 - Lowell Thomas sitting amongst filming equipment. 2 - Lowell Thomas under shade of hut with a microphone, a script, and two native men by his side, 77
    - Page 78: (Color photo). Man shaking hands with Lowell Thomas on dock by the boat, New Guinea officers on dock as well, 78
    - Page 79: Two photos on page. 1 - Lowell and other man from crew standing, surrounded by natives. 2 - Lowell Thomas, natives, and New Guinea officers., 79
    - Page 80: Two photos on page. 1 - Lowell Thomas sitting on boat pointing. 2 - Lowell Thomas standing with painted natives who are holding spears., 80
    - Page 81: Two photos on page. Man smoking a pipe, watching a native man string a bow and arrow. 2 - Native warriors standing in rows., 81
    - Page 82: Two photos on page. 1 - Native women standing in a row. 2 - Boat on water., 82
    - Page 83: Six photos on page. 1 - Three men standing on boat. 2 - Native woman with oar in hand. 3 - Native women with oar in hand. 4 - View from under the roof of the boat; men filming outside of it. 5 - Native woman hacking out a canoe. 6 - Native women making canoes., 83
    - Page 84: Six photos on page. 1 - Group of native women working on canoes. 2 - Men standing on boat with camera equipment. 3 - People on boat. 4 - Native man. 5 - Men on boat, working with lighting equipment. 6 - Three native men, one holding a bow and arrow., 84
    - Page 85: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives canoeing on water near line of huts. 2 - Man filming natives canoeing from boat or dock., 85
    - Page 86: Two photos on page. 1 - Native woman working on a canoe. 2 - Man standing on the bow of the boat., 86
    - Page 87: Two photos on page. 1 - Boat on water. 2 - Native woman canoeing., 87
    - Page 88: Two photos on page. 1 - Natives working on canoes. 2 - Body of water; canoes in distance and huts on lands., 88
    - Page 89: Two photos on page. 1 - Two native women working on a canoe. 2 - Native women working on canoes., 89
    - Page 90: T wo photos on page. 1 - View of hut with canoes passing by it on the water. 2 - Boat on water., 90
    - Page 91: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Boat on water. 2 - Natives in canoes on water. 3 - Natives on dock. 4 - Native woman working on canoe., 91
    - Page 92: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Natives in canoes on water, travelling by huts. 2 - Men on boat by dock. 3 - Close-up of native man holding an some type of instrument. 4 - Native men wearing headdresses and weapons., 92
    - Page 93: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Two children climbing a ladder. 2 - Men standing around half-finished canoes. 3 - Boat docked and people disembarking it. 4 - Group of natives holding shields and spears., 93
    - Page 94: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Native men holding bows and arrows. 2 - Boat on water. 3 - Native man with painted face, holding a spear. 4 - Natives at top of wooden steps that lead up to the hut., 94
    - Page 95: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Native woman paddling a canoe. 2 - Native man standing in a canoe. 3 - Native men standing next to each other. 4 - Native women standing in a row., 95
    - Page 96: Four photos on page. (Negative prints) 1 - Native men sitting. 2 - Natives holding spears in front of large hut. 3 - Two native men. One holding bow and arrow, the other a spear. 4 - Native men holding weapons., 96
  - High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Australian Outback), 1957 - 1958; 2 (Box 1597)
    - Page 1: Six photos on page. 1 -Men climbing a rocky path. 2 - Men climbing a rocky path. 3 - Three trucks in a field. 4 - Man sitting down talking into a radio. 5 - Man sitting. 6 - Man standing amongst rocks., 1
    - Page 2: Three photos on page. 1 - Man 2 - Man sitting at table with a cup of coffee or tea. 3 - Four men digging in ground., 2
    - Page 3: Eight photos on page. 1 - Some native men sitting around their hunted deer. 2 - Some native men sitting around their hunted deer. 3 - Two men sitting by a fire. 4 - Two men sitting by a fire. 5 - View of a wide stretch of land. 6 - Man with sunglasses and a baseball cap. 7 - Man with sunglasses and a baseball cap. 8 - Man sitting down, pouring a bucket of water., 3
    - Page 4: Eight photos on page. 1 - Two men by car. 2 - Two men pouring water into a canteen. 3 - Men observing load of supplies on the back of a truck. 4 - Man holding up a device (camera or compass?) level with his face. 5 - Truck driving in wilderness. 6 - Jeep driving in wilderness 7 - Man holding a device (camera or compass?) level with his face. 8 - Jeep driving in wilderness, 4
    - Page 5: Eight photos on page. 1 - Car driving in wilderness. 2 - Jeep driving in wilderness. 3 - Man looking down, another man in background with camera. 4 - Man with camera. 5 - Man with arm rested out the window of vehicle. 6 - Man sitting on edge of vehicle seat with door open, smoking a cigarette. 7 - Group of natives. 8 - Group of natives in formation., 5
    - Page 6: Eight photos on page. 1 - Natives huddled in circle with weapons on hand. 2 - Men filming the natives. 3 - Some people sitting with their backs against an old house. 4 - Tree and house. 5 - Small village 6 - Some people sitting with their backs against an old house. 7 - Small village. 8 - Small village., 6
    - Page 7: Eight photos on page. 1 - Small village. 2 - Small village. 3 - Creek. 4 - Native man working with tools. 5 - Native man working with tools. 6 - Native man sitting. 7 - Native man sitting. 8 - Men with camera equipment, 7
    - Page 8: Eight photos on page. 1 - Man standing with back to camera. 2 - Cluster of men near Jeep under tree. 3 - Man sitting, using radio on vehicle. 4 - Man sitting, using radio on vehicle. 5 - Man close-up against tree. 6 - Man close-up against tree, looking left., 8
    - Page 9: Eight photos on page. 1 - Line of vehicles in field. 2 - Line of vehicles in field. 3 - People in tent with vehicles parked nearby. 4 - People looking through supplies. 5 - Vehicles lined up in field. 6 - Vehicles lined up in field. 7 - Vehicle driving on dirt road. 8 - Men leaning against vehicle., 9
    - Page 10: Eight photos on page. 1 - Vehicles parked by tree. 2 - Trees. 3 - Trees. 4 - Man sitting. 5 - Rocky hill. 6 - Rocky hill. 7 - Vehicles in field. 8 - One tree., 10
    - Page 11: Two photos on page. 1 - Man leaning against door to vehicle. 2 - Men in standing in a ditch, 11
    - Page 12: Two photos on page. 1 - Men standing with shovels. 2 - Men standing by vehicle, 12
    - Page 13: Two photos on page. 1 - Two men with shovels. 2 - Two men staring out into the distance, 13
    - Page 14: Two photos on page. 1 - Vast land, vehicle driving down dirt road. 2 - Men carrying camera equipment on rocky hill., 14
    - Page 15: Two photos on page. 1 - Men standing with shovels. 2 - Men pouring water into canteens., 15
    - Page 16: Two photos on page. 1 - Men with camera equipment, truck with the writing " Camera 1" one it. 2 - Men pouring water in canteens., 16
    - Page 17: Two photos on page. 1 - Close-up of truck tire. 2 - Men sitting on truck with camera equipment., 17
    - Page 18: Two photos on page. 1 - Man with camera. 2 - Men digging at the gound., 18
    - Page 19: Two photos on page. 1 - Men with shovels. 2 - Man with sunglasses looking into the distance., 19
    - Page 20: Two photos on page. 1 - Men with camera equipment, Lowell Thomas to the right. 2 - Man with sunglasses looking into the distance., 20
    - Page 21: Two photos on page. 1 - Man digging a hole. 2 - Two men examining the grounds., 21
    - Page 22: Two photos on page. 1 - Man standing on top of vehicle. 2 - Men with filming equipment., 22
    - Page 23: Two photos on page. 1 - Man in hole. 2 - Man reaching for something on the ground., 23
    - Page 24: Two photos on page. 1 - Four men standing. 2 - Men with shovels in hole., 24
    - Page 25: Two photos on page. 1 - Looking down into a deep hole on a rocky hillside. 2 - Men with equipment on rocks., 25
    - Page 26: Two photos on page. 1 - Man holding an object in each hand. 2 - Man filming with camera., 26
    - Page 27: Two photos on page. 1 - Two men examining ground. 2 - Weathered rocks., 27
    - Page 28: Two photos on page. 1 - Men gathered and talking. 2 - Side of huge rock., 28
    - Page 29: Two photos on page. 1 - Men carrying man or woman on a cot. 2 - Men gathered by vehicle with equipment, 29
    - Page 30: Two photos on page. 1 - Two men walking, one pointing to the ground. 2 - Man walking by parked vehicles., 30
    - Page 31: Two photos on page. 1 - Men crouched with camera equipment. 2 - Men with camera equipment by vehicles., 31
    - Page 32: Two photos on page. 1 - Men gathered, one man laying on stomach looking through the lens of his camera. 2 - Men trying to loosen vehicle's wheel from ditch, 32
    - Page 33: Two photos on page. 1 - Some vehicles parked, one driving down dirt road. 2 - Men standing around parked truck., 33
    - Page 34: Two photos on page. 1 - Vast field, men in group on the right, lifting another man on a cot. 2 - Men on rocky hill., 34
    - Page 35: Two photos on page. 1 - Men carrying a cot with a man holding a camera. 2 - Men standing around vehicles on dirt road., 35
    - Page 36: Two photos on page. 1 - Four men standing together. 2 - Two men sitting together on ground., 36
    - Page 37: Two photos on page. 1 - Four men standing together. 2 - Three men, one sitting, on slope of a hill., 37
    - Page 38: Two photos on page. 1 - Men working on rocky hill. 2 - Group of men working on a rocky hill., 38